给我点东西。来吧,快。
Give me something. C'mon, quick.
来吧。快点。
C'mon. Hurry up.
坏蛋!帮帮我!
Wretch! Help me out!
快去找个人。
Run and find someone.
帮助我。难道你看不出我做不到吗?哎哟!
Help me. Don't you see I can't make it? Ouch!
哎哟!噢,天哪!一定是坏了。
Ouch! Oh jeez! It must be broken.
哎哟!
Ouch!
不!停止它!你在干什么?白痴!让我来吧!
No! Stop it! What are you doing? Idiot! Let me do it!
运行……快去找个人。
Run... run and find someone.
去……去,快。快!
Go... go, quick. Quick!
你还在等什么?
What the hell are you waiting for?
快点!走吧!
Hurry Up! Go!
你还在等什么?你没看见我快死了吗?
What are you waiting for? Don't you see I'm dying?
你听不见我说话吗?
Can't you hear me?
看看有多少血。
Look how much blood.
多少血啊。
How much blood.
停止。你不能从这里经过。-谁在乎?
Stop. You can't go through here. - Who cares?
你一定在乎。回来。
You must care. Get back.
怎么从这里走呢?
How can one go through here?
多么糟糕的除夕夜!来吧，转过身来。
What a shitty New Year's Eve! C'mon, turn around.
他来了。在那里。你能看见他吗?
Here he is. Over there. Can you see him?
这是他。现在小心点!一件容易的事。
It's him. Be careful now! Easy.
容易……
Easy...
来吧!——哎呀!
C'mon! - Ouch!
进车里，安静点。闭上你的嘴。
Get in the car and be quiet. Keep your mouth shut.
安静!不要害怕。我们不会对你做什么。
Quiet! Don't be afraid. We won't do anything to you.
别伤害他。
Don't hurt him.
给他戴上眼罩。
Get a blindfold for him.
我们快点吧。
Let's hurry up.
不要害怕。
Don't be afraid.
嘿!他什么都能看见。来吧，把他的眼罩弄平。
Hey! He can see everything. C'mon, set his blindfold right.
好的。快。我们走吧。
Ok. Quick. Let's go.
来吧。快。小声点。帮助我。快点。
C'mon. Quick. Keep the noise down. Help me. Hurry up.
就像爬到各各他一样。-闭嘴，混蛋。
It's just like climbing to Golgotha. - Shut up, asshole.
把门关上。
Close the door.
别紧张。
Just take it easy.
别担心。
Don't worry.
但是你们有祸了，大地和海洋!
But woe to you, earth and sea!
你悲伤的时刻到了!当魔鬼降临到你身上时……
Your grieving time has come! As the Devil has come down to you...
…他非常愤怒，因为他知道他只有很短的时间了
...in great fury, since he knows he has but a short time.
当龙看到自己被扔到地上时
When the dragon saw that it had been thrown down to the earth...
…如果我开始追求那个女人
...it started to pursue the woman...
…这个男孩是谁生的
...who had given birth to the male child.
我喜欢你，你知道的。我爱你们所有人。
I like you, you know. I love you all.
我喜欢你说话的方式。我喜欢你的穿着。
I like the way you talk. I like the way you dress.
他也不错。但是我想说……他还不完整。
He's not bad too. But I'd say...he's not complete.
他还不完整。
He's not complete.
在这里。
Here.
好的。他现在看起来好多了。
Ok. He looks better now.
我现在更喜欢他了。更多!
I like him more now. Much more!
你想要牧师?他来了，等着你。
You wanted a priest? Here he is, ready for you.
你现在必须付清你的赌注。
You have to pay off your bet now.
谁把他打扮得像个牧师?
Who has dressed him like a priest?
他揭开了第六印，于是发生了大地震
He broke open the sixth seal and there was a great earthquake.
>太阳变得像黑色的麻布和…
The sun turned as black as dark sackcloth and...
…整个月亮变得像血一样。天上的星星…
...the whole moon became like blood. The stars in the sky...
…像未成熟的无花果被摇散一样落在地上
...fell to the earth like unripe figs shaken loose...
…在强风中从树上掉下来。
...from the tree in a strong wind.
你是谁?是谁?
Who is this? Who is?
第一个，最后一个，活着的那个。
The first one, the last one, the one who lives.
你还需要我吗?
Do you still need me?
你只需要一个牧师来玩吗?
Do you need just a priest to play?
他的脸，他的头发像羊毛或雪一样白
His face, the hair of his head were as white as wool or as snow.
不。现在我没心情了。
No. Now I'm not in the mood anymore.
我不想!我不再要了!
I don't want to! I no longer want!
在那时候，人要求死，却寻不著死
During that time men will seek death but will not find it.
他们渴望死亡，但死亡会逃离他们
They will long to die but death will escape them.
蝗虫的样子就像准备打仗的马
The appearance of the locusts was like that of horses ready for battle.
在他们的头上，他们戴着看起来像金冠的东西
On their heads they wore what looked like crowns of gold...
…他们的脸就像人类的脸
...and their faces were like human faces.
他们的头发就像女人的头发
And they had hair like women's hair...
…他们的牙齿就像狮子的牙齿
...and their teeth were like lions' teeth.
他们的胸部像铁胸甲
They had chests like iron breastplates.
[i bbb]它们翅膀的声音就像许多马车的声音
The sound of their wings was like the one of many horse-drawn chariots...
…冲进战场。他们有像蝎子一样的尾巴
...racing into battle. They had tails like scorpions.
它们的尾巴有能力伤害人类长达5个月之久
With their tails they had power to harm people for five months.
他们有深渊天使作他们的王
They had as their king the angel of the abyss...
…他的名字在希伯来语里是亚巴顿。 . .
...whose name in Hebrew is Abaddon. ..
…在希腊语中是Apollyon.
...and in Greek Apollyon.
说得好!
Well said!
你至少可以为自己辩护或者寻求帮助，神父。
You could have defended yourself at least or asked for help, Father.
或者试图逃跑。
Or tried to escape.
你为什么不这么做，神父?
Why didn't you do that, Father?
你为什么不这么做?
Why didn't you do that?
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
我不知道。
I didn't know.
现在把鞋穿上。它是凉的。
Wear your shoes now. It's cold.
我在那里谁也不认识。
I didn't know anybody there.
但刚开始的时候很有趣。
But it was fun when it started.
但是你被冻住了。来吧，我们跑一跑。
But you're frozen. C'mon, let's make a run.
你现在感觉好点了吗?——是的。
Do you feel better now? - Yes.
我有点累了。
I'm a little bit tired.
你要相信我，我很抱歉……
You have to believe me, I'm so sorry for...
哦，不，毕竟是我的错。
Oh no, it's my fault, after all.
我真不知道我为什么会在这里。
I really don't know why I've found myself around here.
也许你想一个人待着。
Perhaps you wanted to be alone.
午夜时分你扔掉了什么?
What did you throw away around midnight?
哦,没什么。人们仍然坚持向窗外扔东西。
Oh, nothing. People still insist on throwing stuff out the windows.
他们相信明年的情况会好得多。
They're convinced that things will go better and much better next year.
反正我也不相信。
Well, I don't believe it, anyway.
嘿，看那儿!-是牧师!
Hey, look there! - It's a priest!
Ring-a-ring-0“玫瑰…
Ring-a-ring-0'-roses...
我希望这对你来说真的是更好的一年。
I hope that it will be really a better year for you.
我能对牧师许什么愿呢?
What can I wish for a priest?
回去找你的朋友吧。
Get back to your friends.
我为什么要这么做?
Why should I?
现在我只是不想。
Now I just don't want to.
我的兄弟姐妹们，在庆祝神圣的奥秘之前……
My brothers and sisters, before celebrating the sacred mysteries...
…让我们想起我们的罪。
...let's call to mind our sins.
我向全能的上帝忏悔，也向你忏悔……
I confess to almighty God, and to you...
…我的兄弟姐妹们，我因自己的过错而有罪……
...my brothers and sisters, that I've sinned through my own fault...
…在我的思想中，在我的言语中，在我的所作所为中……
...in my thoughts and in my words, in what I've done...
…还有我没能做到的事
...and in what I've failed to do.
我请求圣母玛利亚，永远的处女，所有的天使……
And I ask blessed Mary, ever virgin, all the angels...
…圣徒们，还有你们，我的兄弟姐妹们，请为我祈祷。
...and saints, and you, my brothers and sisters, to pray for me.
愿主与你们同在。-你也一样。
The Lord be with you. - And also with you.
让我们祈祷吧。
Let us pray.
主啊，我们把你仆人夏娃的灵魂托付给你……
We commend to you, Lord, the soul of your servant Eve...
…这样她就能活在你的身体里…
...so that she can live on in you after this life...
…她因人性的弱点而犯下的罪恶……
...and the sins she committed through human weakness...
…可以被你的仁慈所宽恕。
...can be forgiven by your mercy.
借着我们的主耶稣基督。——阿门。
Through our Lord, Jesus Christ. - Amen.
我已经叫你不要再来了。
I had asked you not to come again.
但我必须见到你。
But I had to see you.
我永远地离开了他们。
I left them forever.
为什么?
Why?
我讨厌他们所有人。
I hate them all.
我想要忘记。
I want to forget.
逃跑有什么意义?
What's the point of running away?
你永远也逃不掉了。从来没有
You will be never able to run away. Never
你无处可去。
There's no place where you can go.
你没有希望了。
There's no hope for you.
他们伤害了你这么多。
They have hurt you so much.
他们夺走了你的一切。
They have taken everything from you.
有一天，为了拯救你自己…
And one day, to save yourself...
…也许你会被迫杀人。
...maybe you'll be forced to kill.
杀死……
To kill...
我看到她进来过。
I've seen she's got in here.
嘿，你在干什么?我们在找你。
Hey, what are you doing? We were looking for you.
来吧，我们走吧。-回到我们身边。这是一座教堂。
C'mon, let's go away. - Come back to us. This is a church.
你不知道吗?来吧!我们走吧。-不过她喝醉了。
Don't you know? C'mon! Let's go. - She's drunk, though.
她喝得烂醉如泥。你喝醉了。——不!
She's dead drunk. You're drunk. - No!
你进不去，你喝醉了。停!——不!别烦我!
You can't get in, you're drunk. Stop! - No! Leave me alone!
走开!
Go away!
你所爱的人死后，我埋葬了他们。
I buried your loved ones when they died.
你儿子出生时我给他们施了洗。
I baptized your sons when they were born.
当你们说彼此相爱时，我加入了你们的婚姻。
I joined you in marriage when you said you love each other.
我听到了你的罪恶，却无法帮助你。
And I heard your sins, without being able to help you.
今天……我试着向你忏悔。
Today...I've tried to confess to you.
但我不知道我能不能做到。
But I don't know if I could do it.
我不知道这是否可能。
I don't know if it's possible.
我想告诉你关于我的一切……
I wanted to tell you everything about me...
…我觉得自己不配听到你的罪恶。
...and how I'm feeling unworthy of hearing your sins.
我是如何无力履行我的职责。
How I've been powerless to perform my duties.
我的感受……我还没决定我的任务有多重要。
How I've felt...been undecided about the importance of my mission.
我希望我的最后一次布道会有所不同。
I was hoping that this last sermon of mine would be different.
今天我要向你们告别，因为我要去一个新的教区了。
Today I say goodbye to you, as I will go to a new parish.
我已经做了这个决定……
I've taken this decision...
…因为我认为这样对你比较好……
...as I think it's better for you...
…对我来说也是。
...and for me.
出于谦卑，我真的请求你试着理解我的话……
In all humility, I really ask you to try to understand my words...
…并原谅我。
...and to forgive me.
我希望我值得你的理解……
I hope I've deserved your comprehension...
…感谢我们在一起这么多年。
...for all the years we have been together.
我想我找不到合适的词来形容……
I think I'm unable to find the right words...
…在福音里…而我在自己身上找不到。
...in the gospel...and I can't find them in myself.
我知道我该说什么。
I know what I should say.
但我也知道……我永远不会说的。
But I also know that... I will never say it.
今天我决定离开你，因为……
Today I've decided to leave you because...
…我害怕我的责任。
...I'm afraid of my responsibility.
因为我意识到我帮不了你。
Because I realize that I can't help you.
因为我给不了你你给我的爱。
Because I couldn't give you the same love you gave me.
我想说出真相，但我失败了。
I wanted to tell the truth but I failed.
我试着跟你谈谈基督教的爱……
I tried to talk to you about Christian love...
…但我的话听起来很假。
...but my words sounded fake.
我为此感到羞愧。
And I felt ashamed of that.
就像你对自己的罪恶感到羞耻一样。
Just like you feel ashamed of your sins.
当牧师可不容易。
It's not easy to be a priest.
在一个掺假的世界里，这并不容易……
It's not easy in a world where things are adulterated...
…真相被扭曲了。
...and the truth is distorted.
这就是为什么今天的人们……
That's just why today people...
…当然，还有你们大多数人，你们简单、坦率、忠诚……
...and also most of you, of course, who are simple, frank and faithful...
…被怀疑所麻痹。
...are paralyzed by doubt.
怀疑是人类本性和生活的一部分。
Doubting is part of human nature and life by now.
每个人都必须避免孤独……
Everyone has to avoid loneliness...
…和其他人在一起。
...and to be together with the others.
因为孤独的人对任何事都有怀疑。
Because a lonely man has doubts about anything.
甚至关于上帝。
Even about God.
所以很难帮助他。
And so it's hard to help him.
当一个人失去了自己的信仰……
When a man loses his own faith...
…他甚至不相信自己。
...he doesn't even believe in himself.
他很快就变得虚弱了。
He becomes weak soon...
…他的肉体控制了他。
...as his flesh takes control.
他迷了路，不知不觉中……
He loses his way and without knowing it...
…走到哪儿也去不了，还迷路了。
...takes the road to nowhere and gets lost.
我知道，这些只是混淆的词语。
These are only confused words, I know.
我试着告诉你我的真实感受。
I've tried to tell you what I'm really feeling.
现在我都不知道我这么做是为你好还是为我好。
And now I don't even know if I did it for my or your good.
就是这样。请原谅我。原谅我。
That's it. Forgive me, please. Forgive me.
在这里见到我你感到惊讶吗?
Are you surprised to see me here?
我都不知道……
I don't even know...
…我为什么回来，为什么回来
...why I'm back and what's for.
我只知道我累了……
I only know I'm tired...
…厌倦了逃避。我总是这么做。它总是没用的。
...tired of running away. I always do it. It's always useless.
但你能理解我，不是吗?
But you can understand me, can't you?
因为你也做不到。
Because you can't make it either.
你说对了。你承认了。
You said it. You admitted it.
我太累了。
I'm so tired.
我喝醉了，你看到了吗?
And I'm drunk, you see?
我很困惑。
I'm so confused.
然后我来到这里……
Then I came here...
…我听了你的布道
...and I heard your sermon.
我听了。我得到了。
I listened to it. And I got it.
但那不是牧师的布道。
But it wasn't a sermon by a priest.
你知道为什么吗?
Do you know why?
因为你不是牧师。
Because you're not a priest.
你只是半个牧师，不完全是。
You're only half a priest, not entirely.
我说得对吗，父亲?
Am I right, Father?
不要和我争论……
And do not argue with me...
…因为你得听我的。
...because you have to listen to me.
你必须这么做，即使你不想这么做。
You have to, even if you don't want to.
因为那是你的工作。
Because that's your job.
倾听每个人的意见。每一个人。
Listening to everyone. Everyone.
多么荒谬的……
How absurd...
…和无用……
...and useless...
多么愚蠢……
How stupid...
我在这里做什么?
What am I doing here?
你能告诉我我会变成什么样子吗?
Can you tell me what will become of me?
我会喝酒。
I can drink.
我很擅长喝酒，你知道的。
Well, I'm good at drinking, you know.
然后和我喜欢的人上床。
Then I sleep with whoever I like.
我和我喜欢的人上床。
And I sleep with whoever I like.
怎么了，神父?你感到震惊吗?
What's up, Father? Are you shocked?
没有爱我活不下去。
I can't live without love.
我去不了。
I can't make it.
即使我了解男人。
Even if I know men.
我确实认识他们。
And I do know them.
我不是妻子……
I'm not a wife...
…我不是妓女……
...I'm not a whore...
…我什么都没有。
...I'm nothing.
是的，你说得对。
Yes, you're right.
我是对的。
And I'm right.
每个人都是对的。
And everyone's right.
我在旋转自己…
And I'm spinning myself...
…就像风车一样。
...like a pinwheel.
我已经不知道该如何停下来了。
I no longer know how to stop.
谁能阻止我?
How can one stop me?
只能靠喝酒。
Only by drinking.
我可能会自杀。
I might try to kill myself.
你觉得呢?
Well, what do you think?
你不相信我。
You don't believe me.
你不想相信我!
You don't want to believe me!
你听过多少次这样的忏悔，神父?
How many confessions like this have you listened to, Father?
有多少绝望的，小气的，伪装者的忏悔?
How many confessions by desperate, petty, pretender people?
你为什么要听他们的?
Why are you listening to them?
是的，当然，他们需要帮助。
Yes, sure, they need help.
你说得对，但我和他们不一样。我变得更糟。
You're right but I'm not like them. I'm worse.
你知道为什么吗?
And you know why?
因为我什么都不在乎。
Because I care about nothing.
这不是忏悔。
This is not a confession.
这些都不是我的罪。
And these are not my sins.
这些都是别人犯的罪。
These are the sins by the others.
那是他们的狗屎。
That's their shit.
是的,当然。
Yes, sure.
你也是个男人。
You're a man too.
一个和其他男人一样的男人。
A man like all the other men.
一个穿着黑色衣服的小个子男人……
A little man dressed in black...
…他什么都不懂。
...who understands nothing.
什么都没有。
No nothing.
你现在打算做什么?你会把我赶出去的，是吗?
What are you going to do now? You will kick me out, won't you?
哦，当然，毕竟这对你来说很容易。
Oh, sure, it's easy for you, after all.
你只需要保持温暖，锁在你的小房间里祈祷。
You just need to stay warm, locked in your little room and pray.
祈祷，祈祷，祈祷……祈祷,祈祷……
Pray, pray, pray. . . pray, pray...
你曾经爱过谁吗?
Have you ever loved anybody?
来吧，告诉我真相。
C'mon, tell me the truth.
好了，别害羞。
C'mon, don't be ashamed.
你爱过真正的女人吗?
Have you ever loved a real woman?
爱是很难的。很努力。
It's very hard to love. Very hard.
这几乎是不可能的。
It's almost impossible.
但你在你的讲坛上和我们谈论爱。
But you talk to us about love from your pulpit.
这是给你的。
That's for you.
我偷的。
I stole it.
从你的教堂。
From your church.
因为你要走了。
Because you're leaving.
是的，他必须离开。
Yes, he must leave.
他必须这么做，因为他想这么做。
He must because he wants to.
人们窃窃私语，议论纷纷。
People whisper and talk about it.
但是他们什么也不知道，因为他们只是些可怜的家伙。
But they know nothing, as they're just poor devils.
相反，我知道。我什么都看到了。
Instead I know. I see everything.
不是因为上级，也不是因为共产党。
It's not because of the superiors or or even of the communists, you know.
事实并非如此。事实是他失去了信仰。
The truth is diffent. The truth is that he lost his faith.
我知道牧师是怎样的人。
I do know how priests are.
但他和其他人不一样。
But he's different from the others.
他有胡子。喜欢我。
He has the beard. Like me.
为什么?不是因为昨天，也不是因为今天，事实是他失去了信仰。
Why? It's not due to yesterday or today, the truth is that he lost his faith.
但我理解他。
But I understand him.
让我们以毛为例。
Let's take Mao for example.
我确实对毛很感兴趣。
I'm interested in Mao, indeed.
我亲中。同意了。
I'm pro-Chinese. Agreed.
但我留在这里。
But I stay here.
我是一名牧师，为教会服务。
I'm a sacriston and serve the church.
再见。
Goodbye.
再见,爸爸。
Goodbye, Father.
父亲，你就这样走了?这对我们所有人来说都是一个巨大的悲伤。
Father, you go away like this? It's a big sorrow for all of us.
再见，我的儿子。
Goodbye, my son.
快点回来。你一直都很好。
Come back soon. You've been so good.
再见,爸爸。
Goodbye, Father.
再见,爸爸。祝你旅途愉快。
Goodbye, Father. Have a good trip.
别忘了我们，父亲。
Do not forget about us, Father.
你又在忙什么?
What are you up to again?
你想从我这里得到什么?
What do you want from me?
别烦我!
Leave me alone!
停止它!
Stop it!
我再也受不了了!
I can't take it anymore!
说实话，我对它也不满意。
To be honest, I haven't been happy with it either.
你知道，我太老了。
You know, I'm too old.
这是一个让人无法满足的教区。
It's a parish which gives no satisfaction.
几个人，周围没人。
A few people, nobody all round.
只有岛上的老监狱……
Only the old prison in the isle...
…你偶尔会去的地方。
...where you go every once in a while.
你知道，这很可悲。-真遗憾。
It's sad, you know. - What a pity.
你会习惯的。
You'll get used to that.
另一方面，游客会来的。
Tourists will come, on the other hand.
他们来了，吃了，拍了照，买了汽油，然后又走了。
They come, eat, take pictures, get petrol and leave again.
他们很匆忙。
They are in a hurry.
现在每个人都很着急。
Everyone's in a hurry by now.
还有教会。
Also the Church.
加油站。教会服务。
Service station. Service Church.
是的，离婚，独身，抗议。
Yes, divorce, celibacy, protest.
左翼和右翼牧师。
Left-wing and right-wing priests.
理想危机。
Crisis of ideals.
你需要跟上节奏。
You need to keep the pace.
等一会儿。我给你看样东西。
Wait for a while. I'll show you something.
你觉得呢?一个超现代和自动化的教堂。
What do you think? An ultra-modern and automatic church.
你不会发现它比我更糟。
You won't find it worse than me.
我就是不明白为什么人们跑得那么快。
I just can't get why people are running so fast.
看那边，每天至少发生两起车祸。
Look over there: at least two car accidents occur every day.
还有很多新的交通标志已经安装好了。
And to say that many new traffic signs have been installed.
我去为他们祝福。
I went and blessed them.
这是没有用的。
It was useless.
他们像疯了一样不停地跑。
They keep on running like mad.
速度，速度，速度……
Speed, speed, speed...
谁知道大家都跑到哪里去了?
Who knows where everyone's running?
我的灵魂不要列在罪人之列，我的性命不要列在流人血的人之列
Let not my soul be numbered among sinners or my life among men of blood.
他们的手中是邪恶的阴谋，他们的右手拿着金钱
In whose hands are evil designs, and whose right hands take money.
至于我，却要照我所行的正直而行。求你救我，怜恤我
But as for me, I'll go on in my upright ways: be my saviour and have mercy on me.
这条船出租吗?
Is this boat for rent?
我要去钓鱼。
I need to go fishing.
好吧，你喜欢去哪儿就去哪儿。对我来说也是一样。
Well, go wherever you like. It's the same for me.
但它不适合我。
But it's not for me.
我不会打扰你的。
I won't bother you.
我们走吧?
Shall we go?
我们一定要走远吗?
Must we get far?
你能划多久?
How long can you row?
慢慢地直到黄昏。
Slowly even till dusk.
我只是需要时不时地休息一下。
I just need to get some rest from time to time.
你知道从来没有女人上过这艘船吗?
Do you know that no woman has ever been on this boat?
这种事从没发生在我身上。
It never happened to me.
只有鱼。
Only fishes.
很奇怪，不是吗?
It's strange, isn't it?
其实并不奇怪。
Not so strange, actually.
时代变了。
Times have changed.
现在鱼相当稀少。
Fish is pretty scarce by now.
渔民也是如此。
The same goes for fishermen too.
你得将就一下。
You have to make do.
你会睡吗?
Will you sleep?
去做吧。
Go ahead.
一个人不能一边划船一边说话。
One can't row and speak at the same time.
一个人会累的。
One will get tired.
所以保持安静。
So keep quiet.
我们还得再往前走一点吗?
Do we have to keep going a little bit further?
你不是本地人吧?
You're not from around here, are you?
我逃脱了。
I escaped.
从谁?
From whom?
我逃离了所有人。
I escaped from everybody.
或者说几乎每个人都有。
Or almost from everybody.
你是谁?
Who are you?
假设我现在扮演的是渔夫。
Let's say that I'm playing the fisherman right now.
你在玩什么把戏?
What are you playing at?
不要闭上眼睛。
Do not close your eyes.
不要闭上眼睛……
Do not close your eyes...
不…不要关闭…
No... do not close...
再次见到我你高兴吗，父亲?
Are you happy to see me again, Father?
我会说你是。
I'd say you're.
不，你错了。
No, you're wrong.
我已经告诉过你，我帮不了你。
I've already told you I can do nothing for you.
你来是不对的。
It was wrong of you to come.
如果我想认罪呢?
What if I would like to confess?
我承认那些改过自新并希望得到宽恕的人……
I confess those who are reformed and want to be forgiven...
…而不是那些只想找个共犯的人。
...not those only looking for a partner in their sins.
但你得听我说，神父。
But you have to listen to me, Father.
我听了很多像你这样的女人的忏悔……
I listened to the confessions by many women like you...
…女人感到孤独、被抛弃……
...women feeling alone, abandoned, ...
…被剥削，绝望，无法活下去。
...exploited, hopeless, unable to keep on living.
你觉得自己是个特例，和其他人一样。
And you think you're a special case, just like the others.
你乐于受苦。
You're happy to suffer.
悲伤让你觉得自己很重要，很独特。
Sorrow makes you feel important and unique.
试着诚实一点。
Try to be honest.
你怕我。
You're afraid of me.
你为什么要从我身边跑开?
Why are you running away from me?
你为什么要欺骗自己?
Why are you deceiving yourself?
你知道你对我有多重要吗?
Are you aware of how important you're for me?
我和你在一起变得平和?
That I'm becoming peaceful together with you?
我正在忘记我的过去。
And I'm forgetting my past.
你知道，我非常敬重你。你相信我吗，父亲?
I hold you in such high esteem, you know. Do you believe me, Father?
他们教会我相信。我得说你的感受与我无关。
They taught me to believe. I must say that your feelings don't concern me.
你很清楚我不得不离开多少亲爱的朋友。我爱的人。
You know well how many dear friends I had to leave. People I really loved.
但我是被迫这样做的，因为我不能再继续撒谎了!
But I was forced to do that, as I no longer could keep on lying!
我必须重新找回自我。
I have to find myself again.
我不能给任何人任何东西!
And I can't give anyone anything!
不，这不是真的。
No, it's not true.
你来这里不是为了重新找回自我，而是为了逃避真实的自己。
You aren't here to find yourself again, but to escape from what you're.
为了躲避自己……
To hide from yourself...
…因为你不想存在!
...because you'd like not to exist!
我们永远不可能相互理解。
It will be never possible that we understand each other.
你是女人，我是牧师。
You're a woman and I'm a priest.
不，不是为了这个。
No, it's not for this.
我们不会因为我是女人就互相理解……
We won't understand each other just because I'm a woman...
…而你是个男人。
...and you a man.
没什么好说的了。
There's nothing else to say.
我什么都说了，什么也看不见了。
I've said everything and can't see anything else.
像这样继续。
Go ahead like this.
就像你一直做的那样。
Like you've been doing so far.
足够了。我看不见了。现在我累了。
Enough. I can't see anymore. Now I'm tired.
你也是。
And you too.
我打扰你了吗?
Am I bothering you?
你在祈祷吗?
We re you praying?
不，我只是在想。
No, just thinking.
跪着?
On your knees?
多年来我一直跪着祈祷。
I've been always praying on my knees for years.
但有时我停止祈祷。
But I stopped praying sometimes.
那时我开始思考。
And I was starting to think at that point.
所以现在，即使我只想思考，我也得跪下来。
So now, even if I only want to think, I've to go down on my knees.
你在想我吗，父亲?
Were you thinking about me, Father?
小心，离开那里，你会摔倒的。
Careful, away from there, you might fall down.
再说一遍。
Say it again.
以同样的方式。
In the same way.
小心。
Careful.
远离那里。
Away from there.
你可能会摔倒。
You might fall down.
你很好。
You're good.
你在等我，对吧?
You were waiting for me, weren't you?
来吧，说出来。
C'mon, say it.
愿平安与你同在。
The peace be with you.
还有你。
And also with you.
你相信看手相的人吗?
Do you believe in palmists?
当我还是个孩子的时候……
When I was a child...
…一个吉卜赛女人向我母亲预言有一天……
...a gypsy woman predicted to my mother that one day...
…我会变得富有。
...I would become rich.
很富有。很多钱。
Very rich. Lots of money.
真是个错误。
What a mistake.
所以，从那时起……
So, since that time...
…我不再相信这些东西了。
...I haven't believed in these things anymore.
相反，我相信。
I believe, instead.
我相信一切。
I believe in everything.
我相信黑猫，相信咖啡桌被撞……
I believe in a black cat, in a coffee table being hit...
…我害怕吸血鬼
...and I'm afraid of vampires.
你什么也看不懂，它们只是一些混乱的线条。
There's nothing you can understand there, they are only confused lines.
这不是真的。
That's not true.
不过那个吉普赛女人说得对。
Oh, that gypsy woman was right, though.
我也看到了丰富，非常丰富。
I also see richness, a great richness.
这是你的救命稻草。
Here's your lifeline.
这是幸福线。
This is the line of happiness.
幸福的线真的很深。
The line of happiness is really very deep.
这是心线。
And that's the line of heart.
心的那一段很长很长。
The one of heart is very very long.
看，它往下，往下，往下……
See, it goes down, down, down...
…直到这里。
...until here.
你知道这句谚语吗?
Do you know this saying?
智慧是你的姐妹，谨慎是你的朋友。
Wisdom be your sister and prudence your friend.
我们为什么要躲起来?
Why do we have to hide?
有时候很有趣。
It's funny sometimes.
你为什么把我带到这里来?
Why have you brought me just here?
过来一下。
Come here a minute.
那又怎样?
So what?
我想带你看看我出生的地方。
I wanted to show you where I was born.
在罗马斗兽场?
At the Colosseum?
不，在那边。你能看到那个十字路口吗?
No, over there. Can you see that crossroads?
没有,在哪里?在右边?
No, where? On the right?
不，左边第二个。——是的。
No, the second one on the left. - Yes.
晚上好。你想吃什么?
Good evening. What do you want to eat?
那你今晚就吃我给你带来的吧。
Well, so you'll eat what I bring you this evening.
我要做点好吃的，真正的特色菜。
I'll give something tasty, a true speciality.
专为情侣做的菜。
A dish made especially for lovers.
要不要来点好吃的，真正的特色菜，为情侣特制的菜?
Will you have something tasty, a true speciality, a special dish for lovers?
你为什么那么固执?
Why were you so stubborn?
你穿那条裙子真好看。
You look great in that dress.
我很喜欢你。
I like you so much.
我也很高兴今晚能来到这里。
I'm also very happy to be here tonight.
我又饿又渴。
I'm hungry and thirsty.
我也很高兴我不用在加油站吃饭。
I'm also very happy that I don't have to eat at the service station.
有什么事吗?
What's up?
不要回头。
Do not turn around.
谁在那里？
Who's there?
没关系。
It doesn't matter.
你很好。
You're good.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
我们还没有付帐。
We haven't paid the bill.
我们下次再去。
We shall go there another time.
她死了。
She's dead.
你是牧师吗?
Are you a priest?
不，我不是。
No, I'm not.
把车开到车库去。
Take the car to the garage.
然后上来。
Then come up.
转身……
Turn around...
看着我……
Look at me...
不要害怕……
Don't be afraid...
转身……
Turn around...
看着我……
Look at me...
不要害怕……
Don't be afraid...
你不必……
Yo don't have to...
太迟了。
It's too late.
我不再年轻了。
I'm not young anymore.
我现在已经无法改变我的生活了。
I can no longer change my life by now.
我每天晚上都感到恐惧和痛苦。
I'm always feeling fear and anguish every night.
一切都让我害怕。
Everything scares me.
不，不是所有的，但是……
No, not everything, but...
…事情将如何发展，直到……
...how things will be till...
…直到最后。我预见每一刻，每一天。
...till the end. I foresee every moment, every day.
没有出路了。
There's no way out.
你真漂亮。
You're so beautiful.
喜欢总是。就像往常一样，你突然出现了。
Like always. And, like always, you come up all of a sudden.
你知道我为什么来吗?
Do you know why I've come?
不，一点也不。
No, not at all.
假设我可以想象它。
Well, let's say that I can imagine it.
你需要钱，所以你回到了谷仓。
You need money and so you head back to the barn.
当我需要的时候，我会问你的。
When I need it, I will ask you.
很好。
Very well.
如果不是为了钱，那又怎样?
And if it's not about the money, so what?
不，我只是想让你下定决心同意我离婚。
No, I just want you to make up your mind and grant me a divorce.
毕竟，这对你来说只是个价格问题。
It's just a matter of a price for you, after all.
当然!只是价格的问题。
Sure! Just a matter of a price.
你让我付出了很多，所以我没有理由要失去你。
You has cost me a lot, so there's no reason why I'd have to lose you.
不，一件珍贵的东西不能就这样浪费掉。
No, a precious object is not to be wasted like that.
此外，你必须考虑到我对你的感觉，即使是现在。
Moreover, you must consider what I feel for you, even now.
拜托，拜托。
Please, come on.
不管怎样，这还不是全部。
That's not all, anyway.
还有另一个原因。
There's another reason.
当我遇见你的时候，你是我的替补。
When I met you, you were a third string.
我是说你什么都不是。
I mean you were nothing.
我把你介绍给重要人物。
I've introduced you to important people.
我用我的爱创造了你……
I've made you with my love...
…还有我的钱。
...and with my money.
为什么?这不是真的吗?
Why? Isn't that true?
这就是我恨你的原因，你很清楚。
That's just why I hate you and you know it very well.
是这个原因吗?真的吗?
Is this the reason? Really?
是的，就是这样。
Yes, that's it.
你从没想过把我看得很高。
You never wanted to think highly of me.
我一直都是你的玩具。
I've always been a toy for you.
因为我喜欢你那样。
Because I liked you like that.
你真是无与伦比。
You're really inimitable.
那你有什么建议?
Well, what are you proposing?
我知道我们有进展了。
I see that now we're getting somewhere.
好吧，我的建议是。
Well, here's my proposition.
我们同意离婚。
We will agree with the divorce.
唯一的条件是你要成为我的爱人。
The only condition is that you'll become my lover.
现在你是我的妻子……
Now you're my wife...
…你有很多情人。
...you have got many lovers.
然后你就会成为另一个男人的妻子，但是……
Then you'll be the wife of another man but...
…你要和我睡。
...you will sleep with me.
这很合理，不是吗?
It's reasonable, isn't it?
你真让我恶心。
You make me sick.
但我爱你……代替。
But I love you... instead.
因为男人不是由女人而来的
For man did not come from woman...
…但是女人来自男人。
...but woman from man.
男人也不是为女人而创造的，…
Nor was man created for woman, ...
…但是女人对男人。
...but woman for man.
因此，女人的头上应该有一个男人权威的标志，…
Hence a woman should have a sign of authority of man on her head, ...
…因为天使。
...because of the angels.
另一方面，女人也不是独立于男人之外的
On the other hand, woman is not independent of man...
…或在主里的男人或女人。
...or man of woman in the Lord.
因为正如女人是从男人而来的
For just as woman came from man...
…所以男人是由女人所生的
...so man is born of woman.
万物都是出于神
And all things are from God.
你能划多久?
How long can you row?
我不知道。
I don't know.
我打赌这是圣经里的话。
I bet it was a quote from the Bible.
圣保罗写给哥林多人的第一封信。
From St. Paul's First Letter to the Corinthians.
就是这样。
That's it.
再见!
Goodbye!
我忘了告诉你我游泳游得很好。
I forgot to tell you that I'm a very good swimmer.
今天早上刚抓到的。
Just caught this morning.
是的，就像我以前在市场上买的鱼一样。
Yes, like the fish I use to buy at the market.
你知道，这里很好。
It's nice here, you know.
你打算在这间公寓里住很长时间吗?
Are you going to stay in this apartment for a long time?
我必须再见到你。-你疯了!
I had to see you again. - You crazy!
别烦我。
Leave me alone.
你在我的脑海里挥之不去。
You're stuck in my head.
事情本不必这样结束的……
It didn't have to end like this...
到这里来。
Come here.
走开!-别动。
Go away! - Stay still.
我再也不想了!- - - - - -什么? !
I no longer want to! - What?!
我不想!——安静。
I don't want to! - Quiet.
我说不!
I said no!
她也是你的女人吗?
Is she your woman too?
我，你和她。所以我们有三个人。
Me, you and her. Hence there's three of us.
你这个笨蛋!白痴!
You dumb ass! Idiot!
我已经和她睡过了!她想要我。
I've been already sleeping with her! She wanted me.
你明白吗?
Do you understand that?
她想要我!我都不用问她。
She wanted me! I didn't even have to ask her.
她是惊人的。
She's amazing.
她像女神一样做爱。
She makes love like a goddess.
你这个哭哭啼啼的绿帽子。
You crying cuckold.
他是对的。
He's right.
都是你的错。邪恶在你身上，你不想改变。
It's your fault. Evil is in you and you don't want to change.
所以像你这样的女人永远不想改变!
So women like you never want to change!
你们都是一样的!都一样!
You are all the same! All the same!
我跟踪你来不是因为你说得对。
I didn't follow you here because you're right.
不是那样的。
It's not like that.
看着我。
Look at me.
好吧。
All right.
所以我在这里等你。
So I'll wait for you here.
欢迎您,爸爸。
Welcome, Father.
进来。
Come in.
嘿!听。
Hey! Listen.
你有烟吗?
Do you have a cigarette?
美丽的…
Beautiful...
不，别走。
No, don't go away.
让我看看。-放开我!
Let me see it. - Let me go!
等待。——不!
Wait. - No!
你要去哪里?——够了!
Where are you going? - Enough!
等等!你要去哪里?
Wait! Where are you going?
到这里来。
Come here.
放开我!
Let me go!
你在干什么，神父?
What are you doing, Father?
把钥匙还给我。来吧!
Give back the keys. Come on!
那是监狱里最古老的地方。
That's the oldest part of the prison.
它已经很多年没有被使用了。
It's hasn't been used for many years now.
总有一天它会崩溃。
It will collapse one day.
被判无期徒刑的囚犯住在这里。
Life sentenced prisoners stay here.
原谅我。这几天我想了很多。
Forgive me. I've been doing a lot of thinking these past few days.
现在我要告诉你…
And now I have to tell you that...
什么也别说。我知道这对你来说不可能。
Don't say anything. I know it's impossible for you.
当你在讲坛上讲话时，你可以向你的奉献者谈论爱。
You can talk about love to your devotees, when speaking from the pulpit.
但你不能对一个单身女人这么说。
But you can't tell that to a single woman.
等待。
Wait.
等一下。呆着别动!
Wait for a moment. Stay still!
这很简单。那么简单。
It's so easy. So simple.
每天都有数以百万计的人对彼此说这句话。
Millions of people say that to each other every day.
不，我不能代替你说。
No, I can't say that instead of you.
你必须这么说。
You have to say that.
你找他干什么?你为什么总缠着他?放开他!
What do you seek of him? Why are you always stuck to him? Let him go!
他不适合你!-我就是不明白。放开我!
He's not for you! - I just don't get it. Let me go!
是的，你明白了。他是我儿子。
Yes, you do get it. He's my son.
我和上帝的儿子，仅此而已!现在明白了吗?
My and God's son and nothing else! Got it now?
他已经为我——他的母亲——做了牧师。他爱我。
He has become a priest for me, his mother. And he loves me.
他曾经很快乐……平和快乐。
Once he was happy... Peaceful and happy.
你为什么不放过他?我求你了。
Why don't you leave him alone? I beg you.
小心，如果你毁了他或者你想这么做，我会杀了你，我有能力。
Beware, if you ruin him or if you want to, I'll kill you, I'm able to.
你是个坏女人。
You're a bad woman.
你是个坏妈妈。
And you're a bad mother.
你会杀了我，不是吗?
You would kill me, wouldn't you?
你是怎么猜到的?
How could you guess that?
我了解你。
I know you.
至少你会承认我是个听话的丈夫。
At least you'd acknowledge that I'm an obedient husband.
你打电话给我，我就赶过来了。
You've called me and I've just rushed over here.
你知道我差点就想你了吗?
You know that I've almost missed you?
好吧，你愿意和我一起回去吗?
Well, will you come back with me?
不，我不是必须成为你的爱人吗?
No, didn't I have to become your lover?
什么时候?
When?
即使是现在，如果你愿意。
Even now, if you want.
我不相信你。
I don't trust you.
我也不相信你。
I don't trust you either.
我们要去哪里?
Well, where are we going?
你说"在哪儿"是什么意思?当然是去你家了。
What do you mean "where"? To your place, of course.
不是说好了吗?
Wasn't that the deal?
哎哟!
Ouch!
帮我一下。快。帮帮我。
Give me a hand. Quick. Help me out.
我不能……我动不了了。
I can't... I can't move.
你为什么只是站在那里?
Why are you just standing there?
给别人打电话。难道你看不出我做不到吗?哎哟!该死的!
Call people or someone. Don't you see I can't make it? Ouch! Damn!
你在干什么?哎哟!
What are you doing? Ouch!
停止它!白痴!
Stop it! Idiot!
寻求帮助。快点。
Ask for help. Hurry up.
停车!做点什么!来吧!快……
Stop a car! Do something! Come on! Quick...
你在看什么?
What are you staring at?
走吧!快跑!
Go! Run!
你还在等什么?难道你看不见我快死了吗?
What the hell are you waiting for? Can't you see I'm dying?
你听不见我说话吗?
Can't you hear me?
看看有多少血。
Look how much blood.
多少血啊……
How much blood...
你想要什么?我不能忏悔你。
What do you want? I can't confess you.
等待。我杀了我丈夫。
Wait. I've killed my husband.
我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
我都是为了你!对我们来说!我现在自由了!
I did that for you! For us! I'm free now!
你该死，你犯了最严重的罪……
You're damned, you committed the worst sin...
我才不在乎呢!
I don't even care!
别那样说，别那样说话。
Do not say that, do not talk like that.
低下头。你能听到我说话吗?跟我念:我的错……
Bow your head. Can you hear me? Repeat after me: mea culpa...
你就不能说点别的吗?
Can't you say anything else?
闭嘴!不要亵渎!
Shut up! Don't blaspheme!
我的错，我的错，我最大的错，我的错，我的错……
Mea culpa, mea culpa, mea maxima culpa, mea culpa, mea culpa...
没用的!
It will be no use!
求你不要折磨我。
Please, do not torment me.
我不能赦免你。我不能原谅你。
I can't absolve you. I can't forgive you.
我不能和你呆在一起。
I can't stay with you.
上帝啊，宽恕我的罪过吧。
God, forgive my sins.
你也原谅了我。
And you forgive me as well.
主啊，在这试炼中帮助我。
Lord, help me in this trial.
这样我就不会永远迷路了。主啊，请原谅我。
So that I won't get lost forever. Forgive me, Lord.
主啊，听我的祷告。请不要拒绝我的帮助。
Lord, hear my prayer. Do not deny me your help.
听我的召唤。我在这里只是短暂的客人。
Listen to my call. I'm your guest here only for a short time.
让我们祈祷吧。
Let us pray.
主啊，我既领受了……
Having received, o Lord...
…救赎你的圣礼……
...the sacrament of your salvation...
…我们恳求你，让圣母保佑我们吧。
...we beg you, let the Blessed Virgin of the Street protect us.
我们总想留在他多情的保护下。
Under whose amorous protection we always want to stay.
在她多情的保护下…我们总是想留下来。
Under whose amorous protection ...we always want to stay.
在他的多情保护下，我们总是想要……
Under whose amorous protection we always want...
你为什么不想爱我?
Why don't you want to love me?
我爱你。就像我爱其他男人一样。
I love you. Like I love all the other men.
你是个骗子。
You're a liar.
你不可能以同样的方式爱每一个人。
You can't love everyone in the same way.
你不可能像我爱你那样爱别人。
And you can't love the others in the same way I love you.
你是亵渎神明的。
You're blasphemous.
好的!够了!别再提这件事了。
Ok! That's enough! Let's say no more about it.
我再也不会见你了。
Never again.
你现在在干什么?
What are you doing now?
我想去游泳。
I want to take a swim.
不,请。
No, please.
如果你怕我自杀，你也来吧。
If you're afraid I'll kill myself, you come too.
拜托!别这么做!
Please! Don't do it!
如果你愿意，你还是可以救我的。
You can still save me, if you want.
你为什么不敢看我?
Why are you afraid of looking at me?
你喝醉了。
You're drunk.
你很可笑。
And you're ridiculous.
你是可笑的!一个可笑的牧师!一个可笑的人!
You're ridiculous! A ridiculous priest! And a ridiculous man!
你是可笑的!
You're ridiculous!
做得好!来了!
Well done! Come!
你能做到的!
You can do it!
来吧!潜水!
Come on! Dive!
而现在……
And now...
现在你得告诉我真相。
Now you have to tell me the truth.
你喜欢我吗?
Do you like me?
很多。
A lot.
我们离得太远了!
We're too far out!
我们回去好吗?
Shall we head back?
我累了。
I'm tired.
停!
Stop!
你能听到我说话吗?回来!
Can you hear me? Come back!
停!回来!
Stop! Come back!
停!
Stop!
2018年4月，魁地姆粉丝字幕
Fansubbed by quidtum, April 2018